Iván Olivares Rojas

https://iolivares.com

Technical Lead and front-end software developer

hi@iolivares.com • O +56 9 6303 4970 • Im /ivanolivaresrojas • O /ivolivares

ABOUT

I'm a Software Engineer centered on producing beautiful interfaces and experiences for consumers. Currently working as Technical Lead and front-end software developer at Globant in Santiago, Chile. I'm also an amateur photographer, a community builder enthusiast and volunteer for non-profit organizations.

I have more than 7 years of work experience working in different industries such as digital marketing, e-commerce, streaming (video and audio) for high concurrency users and recently the airline industry.

Also, in the latest years I've worked in agile methodologies, proud of being a member of excellence teams where I'm outstanding for my commitment, leadership, focus on objectives and global vision through different roles and technologies.

ACHIVEMENTS

2016 - 2018

In 2018 I received the Globant award: "Most rewarded Glober", internally know as "Glober of the year". This award identifies the most recognized employee in "StarMeUp" (www.starmeup.com) by others

In 2017 I received the Globant award: "Think Big" and in that same year, I started to lead initiatives with the communities of developers, adding to the presence of the Globant map in Chile and the integration of Globers in this constantly-growing location. I was also recognized by the company as "Most Valuable Player".

In 2016 I was given the "Constantly Innovative" award by Globant. In that same year, I was elected Ambassador in Chile for "Globant Labs", the innovation center of Globant.

SKILLS

Programming languages

Proficient with: JavaScript, PHP (7 years). Familiar with: Python, Java, Objective-C, Swift, .NET.

Libraries / Platforms

Node.JS, ExpressJS, Restify, Socket.io, Mongoose, Lodash, MomentJS, D3.js, Gulp, Grunt, Webpack, ReactJS, React Native, Ionic, Redux, AngularJS, Jest, Mocha, Enzyme, Chai, Sinon, jQuery, Less, Google Maps Platform (certified), serverless.

Markup / Templating

HTML, CSS, Sass, Less, Jade, Mustache, Bootstrap.

Data / databases

Proficient with: MySQL (7 years), MongoDB (3 years), Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager (certified).

Familiar with: SQL Server, Elasticsearch, Google BigQuery, Machine

DevOps / infrastructure

Proficient with: Docker, Jenkins, CI/CD, (micro-)service oriented

Familiar with: Kubernetes, Amazon Web Services, Cloudflare, On-premise VPS, Google Cloud Platform.

Others software development skills

Unix/Linux, Functional programming, RESTful APIs Development, Test-driven development, Behavior-driven development, Accessibility (W3C Standard), Agile methodologies (Scrum Developer Certified - SDC).

EDUCATION

Technical degree of computer science engineering.

I decided not to continue with my computer science studies because I'm more of an autodidact and I think my experience working in software development exceeds the knowledge I could have gotten from my country's universities. However, I never stop reading and learning on my own.

Languages

English: advanced professional proficiency. Spanish: native proficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Globant

SOFTWARE DESIGNER - FRONT-END DEVELOPER

2018 - present

Accountable for define and implement the overall architecture of web applications, implement best practices and ensure they're followed, be a referring in web applications development and have deep knowledge of its core technologies (JavaScript, HTML, CSS), frameworks, and development tools.

TECHNICAL LEAD

Team leader, accountable for the growth of the people that compose it, of guarantee right technical decisions, to follow the best practices in software development and having the big picture of project, supporting the business areas to considerate the technological decisions in the roadmap.

Main projects developed in this period (2017 - present): "New Digital Analytics for LATAM Airlines", I was work in the build a new model for measure digital platforms of large scale (millions of users and a lot of teams developing software), working with Google Marketing Platform (Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager mainly) and Google Cloud Platform (Google Big Query and other big-data platforms).

SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Software developer of web applications, coding with authonomy, considering the performance issues, ensure code quality, and best practices. Responsible for have a continuous contact with customers on system design, having sound knowledge of customers' business and information flows, suggesting changes in customers' environment to achieve project objectives.

Main projects developed in this period: "New LATAM Travel for booking Hotels", developed with React JS, Redux, NodeJS, among other technologies.

SEMI SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Software developer of web applications, working with minimum supervision. Working closely with designers to turn their static designs into functional user interfaces. Writing modular, scalable, testable Javascript, HTML and CSS. Collaborate with backend developers in order to integrate the business logic.

Main projects developed in this period: "New applications for LATAM Pass / LATAM Fidelidade (fidelization programs of LATAM Airlines)." Application "account status" for see how muchs points users was acumulate in different periods, developed with JavaScript, Mustache, Bootstrap, Less, Google Analytics, among other technologies.

Mediastream

SEMI SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

2014 - 2015

Front-end and Back-end Development of the different products related to high demand audio and video streaming (OvP, OTT, WebChannels, among others).

Cooperation with the management and organization of events in Chile, Brazil and Colombia. Maintenance and development of mobile applications for iOS (native).

Main technologies worked in this period: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Socket.io, Objective-C, PHP, MySQL, Google Analytics, among others.

STARTUPS CO-FOUNDER

Maxis (Tech and Consulting)

2010 - 2014

First try: Foundation and chief level of the directive board. In it we build, together with a great team, what would be the first product of success in my history as an entrepreneur. The previous thing involved a series of experiences, travel, analysis, research, creation, re-invention and meetings with possible clients and investors, which gave me a great field experience for the creation of products.

Second try: Foundation and management. In it was we achieved the staging of a product (mobile app: "descubri") which, after being presented to the community, got a private investment of 8,000 USD, in addition to multiple recognitions by the Government of Chile (SERCOTEC and "Imagina Chile").